# **Christian Oudard**

christian.oudard@gmail.com http://github.com/christian-oudard/

#### **Summary**

I solve business problems by creating clear understanding, and turning that understanding into software. I'm a computer systems generalist with over 10 years of experience, and numerous personal software projects. My areas of interest include full stack web development, databases, data analysis, and machine learning. I care deeply about communicating empathetically, in a way that respects the humanity of those I work with. Outside of software, let's talk about math, philosophy, linguistics, biomechanics, or neuroscience.

### Experience

• Disqus Data Engineer

June 2016 –December 2016

- Part of a three-person team responsible for a data analysis pipeline handling tens of millions of events per day. The pipeline is built using Kafka, Storm, S3, Hive, and Redshift.
- Backend feature development in Python, including work on advertisement serving.
- Infer inc. Full-stack Engineer

July 2015-September 2015

- Worked on Infer's main product which manages machine learning sales models.
- Coded improvements to the CoffeeScript frontend interface as well as the Python backend.
- TinyCo Backend Engineer

September 2012-January 2014

- Coded complete rewrites of several major systems, such as the code deployment system and game configuration server.
- Interviewed new employees to help grow the team from 3 to 8.
- Mentored junior backend engineers and mobile engineers, especially in Python and Django.
- Instituted the usage of better database migration practices, and better unit testing.
- Scribd Software Engineer

January 2012–August 2012

- Worked as a Ruby on Rails and Javascript engineer on a team of 12.
- Worked with a huge mysql database. We ran out of 32-bit unsigned primary keys on one of our tables.
- Responsibilities included the Scribd Developer API, internal mobile client API, and the embedded document viewer.
- PolicyStat Software Engineer

October 2008–January 2012

- Joined at a very early stage, when there was just the CTO, the CEO, and a single client. When I left, we had over a hundred hospitals as customers.
- Did full-stack development, including server administration on Amazon AWS, Django backend, and web frontend using jQuery and CSS
- With the CTO, completely rewrote the codebase from PHP to Python/Django.
- Developed an algorithm for diffing structured documents in HTML.

## Education

• University of Louisville Bachelors of Computer Science

Fall 2004–Spring 2008

## **Skills**

- Languages: Python, Haskell, Ruby, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Shell Script
- Libraries: Django, SciPy, Ruby on Rails, jQuery
- Tools: Linux, Git, Puppet, Amazon Web Services (AWS)